Morning.
Mezato.
G-good morning...
Why didn't you show up yesterday?
Morning, Mob.
Sorry, yesterday...
I just totally forgot.
You... forgot?
There was an executive meeting
the day before the assembly,
and he just showed up there.
The real founder.
Huh?
I'm sorry for mistaking you as the founder
and dragging you into all this.
It's okay now.
What do you mean, okay?
What's going on?
(MOB MOB WOW!)
I realized that our youth is grey
The origin of this uneasiness
Is yet unknown
Trains of emotions keep running
Through my brain
Struggling through this adolescence
Don't disturb my deep psyche
Who is that behind you?
Opposing ideas creates distortion
Exorcise all the sorrow
So, do what you can now
My life
Finally, break it down
(Want) Both greed
(Young) And honesty
(Burn) Are growing
(1) On this chest of mine
(Trance) I'm not waking up
(Chance) I want to wake up
(Stance) These two different faces of mine
(1) Are standing back-to-back
Taking things as it is
In this free relation where
We resent each other
Once these two become one
That smile becomes one
And only "1"
(MOB MOB WOW!)
"1"
One and only "1"
(MOB MOB WOW!)
"1"
One and only "1"
(Divine Tree 1
~The Founder Appears~)
My bad, really. I totally forgot.
I really have no idea how
I could forget at the last minute.
Is it something related to
the Psycho Helmet Religion?
Oh, how did you know?
Yesterday, I was solicited
into a seminar in the city,
but once I went, I ended up more
interested in it than in space.
Everyone, from now on,
we're no longer the Brainwave Club,
we'll be Psycho Helmet Religion
Salt Mid Branch!
Really?
And what do we do as that?
We'll offer prayer to
the Psycho Helmet Club.
They say five minutes per day
would give benefits.
Really? Just like that?
So, that Psycho Helmet Religion
meeting yesterday?
The broadcast video has been watched
over two million times.
Well?
That's the guy that becomes their founder.
You know him?
No, not at all.
He has to be a psychic.
After that, all the other groups become
part of the religion just like that.
Unfortunately, now that he's the founder,
you can't take that position anymore.
Oh well, whatever.
You're not the type to do
that kind of thing, anyway.
Anyway, you said there's something
you want to talk about.
Oh, about that.
Pictures of buildings?
Wow, they have big cracks.
Mysterious structural deterioration
phenomenon.
Once I checked the place,
it wasn't any normal structural defect.
The cause is plant roots.
Now that I think again,
that building was a victim of it, too.
The roots that have appeared
all over the city
they pierces through roads and reinforced
concrete in search of nutrients.
I thought it was an invasive species,
but it's actually coming from
the worst place possible.
The culprit is none other than the
very thing taking everyone's attention.
The Divine Tree.
-That broccoli?
-That's right!
That means if we ignore that thing,
all our jobs will be nothing
but building investigations.
Is it that bad?
They take lots of effort,
but barely make money, you know.
Not to mention, we're a bit responsible
about that thing in the first place.
Mob.
Help me with this.
We're going to destroy that broccoli.
Okay.
Good afternoon. Please take this.
Huh? What's this?
It's part of the Divine Tree
that has been powdered.
It's very good as nourishment.
They've added new menus!
I want to eat the Divine Tree parfait!
-It's the Divine Tree croquette!
-I heard they're giving free samples.
I'm feeling pretty pumped ever since
I got to this Seasoning City.
-What's that?
-Divine Tree candy, apparently.
-Is it good?
-What flavor?
-This will be pretty good with a sauce.
-Who needs sauce for this?
Handmade cookies, huh?
"I've used powdered Divine Tree
that's really good for vitality."
"Please eat some and get healthy."
Didn't they also give out
Divine Tree powder at the station?
Just so-so.
Probably just the usual placebo product.
Things like this are pretty nice.
The Divine Tree... is amazing...
Long live... Lord Psycho Helmet...
It's a powerful brainwashing
that takes control of emotions!
They're handing things
mixed with this?!
You won't get away with this!
You've made me angry!
The brainwash wave is emitted from
the direction of the Divine Tree.
I'll purge it and free this city!
In here, huh?
Sorry, but I'm opening a hole here.
A barrier?!
Ivies?!
Seems like you were waiting for me.
Wait, is that you, Kageyama?
Nah, he just looks like him.
Who are you?
What are you doing here?
What do you mean, who?
I...
...am obviously God.
God... A true God...
That's right...
Lord Psycho Helmet,
pardon my rudeness.
I beg your forgiveness.
You damaged the Divine Tree
that strengthen my existence.
I'll let you go this time. Go home.
Thank you very much.
Be more discipline
in your worship from now on.
Yes...
Worship... God...
Psycho Helmet... Divine Tree...
Religion...
Empty...?
Another one that is
annoying to deal with.
How dare you!
You didn't just try
to brainwash me once, but twice.
That is not brainwashing,
but a blessing.
I'm offering commoners that have nothing
and those looking for a place
a sanctuary for their heart.
Hey, are you trying to kill me?
It's not like you're a human, anyway.
That is correct.
I am a God!
Trying to fight God is insanity!
Rethink this again!
Another brainwashing...?
That's enough of you!
Your brainwashing wave.
It forcefully raises a sense of awe
toward the Psycho Helmet Religion.
But you won't get brainwashed if you
can push it back with strong emotion.
Here I come.
I already had my fill
of people that try to conquer
others with power.
Doing that won't make you a God.
Or even a protagonist.
That's not how you do it.
All right, time to figure out who it is.
Is this...?
Minegishi, you can take a break now.
Okay.
-Manager.
-What is it?
The plants are strange.
The flowers were fine this morning,
but now they're withering.
They're losing their vigor, as if
their life essence is being sucked dry.
-I think we need to find the cause...
-Minegishi.
I told you it's break time,
so take a break already.
(Smiley Flower Arrangement)
Okay...
I wasn't expecting a proper job
to be this tough.
Even the roadside weed
is getting weaker.
Not to mention, the cracks
are larger than yesterday.
What's the cause?
Which tree are you from?
I see.
The Divine Tree.
So you're taking energy
from all the plants in the city.
The soil will die if I leave it alone.
Good thing I noticed it early.
You've grown too greedy.
This is an order.
You may no longer...
Hey, Minegishi, how much longer
are you going to take a break?
Huh? Minegishi?
It can't be...
So persistent. How much longer
are you going to keep regenerating?
You can't stop me.
Don't you agree, Hanazawa?
I see now...
You really are
a good-for-nothing evil spirit.
What are you trying to do
with that look,
Dimple?
I used the Divine Tree's trunk
to image myself
based on Psycho Helmet's icon.
The followers cannot see me
in spirit form, after all.
What's your goal?
Does Kageyama know about
you going out of control?
This has nothing to do with Shigeo.
My goal has always been
one and the same.
To be a God in this modern era.
I see, what a shame.
I have to erase you once again.
I'll tell Kageyama that you moved
to the afterlife peacefully.
This is goodbye!
Don't you think something is weird?
The atmosphere in the city.
It's as if we're being watched.
Right, you said you're getting
popular lately, aren't you?
Everyone gets a bit too
self-conscious once in their life,
but I suggest you don't say that out loud.
You'll regret it in a couple of years.
How are we going
to destroy that broccoli?
Well, I've made a plan.
Simple enough, right?
Um, so I have to carry it to the sea?
Yeah. I will look out for your safety
and make sure you reach it.
This is going to be a tiring job.
It would be great if someone can help.
Serizawa gonna be in his night school...
What about your brother?
Ritsu...
There's a student council meeting today,
so he might still be at school.
-Ritsu.
-Hey.
Isn't carrying that thing
a bit too much, Brother?
I once carried a piano
together with others.
Doing it alone would be impossible,
but we managed to do it
by working together.
That's why, we should be able to do it.
Get your Divine Tree powder here.
Take it, it's good for your health.
What's wrong?
You're not up to it?
-No, I...
-I'm begging you, Ritsu.
If we don't do anything, Seasoning City
might end up becoming uninhabitable.
My mum once planted
a watermelon in her yard,
and she said it ended up
killing all the other plants.
Not to mention its size.
It'll immediately take all the nutrients.
Just like that.
Fine, fine. I get it. I'll help.
Is something wrong?
Well, it's...
Praying time?
What's that supposed to be?
Basically we're praying so that
we can live the day happily.
What are you talking about?
Are you sane, Makihara?
Besides, who are you praying to?
We pray to Lord Psycho Helmet
that lives inside the Divine Tree.
-Who agrees with me?
-Hey, Makihara...
-I agree.
I agree.
Hang on, everyone!
Are you all thinking straight?!
-This stupid thing...
-Now now,
you don't have to reject it so hard.
I understand new opinions
are not easy to just accept.
Kamuro...
Brother, do you know about
the Psycho Helmet Religion?
Huh? Are you also interested in that?
Of course not. But it seems like there
are a lot of their followers at school.
I just find their spread
to be weirdly fast.
And the thing they... worship,
I think, is the Divine Tree.
So that means getting rid of the broccoli
would antagonize them.
But as far as I checked,
they seemed pretty harmless.
Selling merchandise, sharing opinions...
Maybe less of a religion and
more of a group of hobbyists.
Something like a group of people
with similar interests having fun.
That's why I'm saying they're suspicious.
Of course, we need to be careful of them.
We might need to think
of a counter plan.
Oh well, let's just do it quickly
and immediately run away.
My head hurts!
I'm going to need some sugar.
You brought candies to school, Ritsu?
Oh, this?
I got these from the student
council president.
Kageyama.
-Take this before you go home.
-What are those?
Apparently, it's a product made
for city promotion.
My dad got a lot of samples
from a meeting.
-I'll take them.
-Thank you.
Give it a try, Brother.
Thank you.
Have some too, Reigen.
O-oh? I'll have it later.
Me too, I'll have it later.
Once we finished pulling the broccoli.
Before that,
can we go somewhere first?
You're walking pretty fast.
Where are we going, Ritsu?
Ritsu?
(Seasoning City Meeting Hall)
It's in here.
I'd like to introduce you
to some people.
Isn't this the city's meeting hall?
Who are they, Ritsu?
They're from the Psycho Helmet Religion.
What?
Brother, let's rethink this again...
W-what do you mean?
There's no use playing dumb.
How could you even think
about removing the Divine Tree?
The Divine Tree enriches everyone's heart.
This city needs the Divine Tree.
Hang on a sec!
When did you inform these guys?
Ritsu, what is going on?
I just thought that I need
to protect the Divine Tree.
Then I had an inkling that
everyone would be here.
And what are you planning to do
by bringing us here?
That candy!
Have a seat, Brother.
You too, Reigen.
Here, we prepared some tea for you.
You don't need to be so wary.
Let's talk about this peacefully, okay?
So they won't even listen for a bit...
Do we really need to run that quickly?
If we stayed there, we might turn
into followers via group hypnotism.
-Take out the candy you have.
-Candy?
There's a ton of this thing
in that room.
Ritsu might've been
brainwashed by these things.
Ritsu got brainwashed?
I can't just leave him be.
Calm down, I don't think
it causes any real harm yet,
-We should proceed...
-Hey, you two!
I suggest you don't do anything futile.
Lord Psycho Helmet sees all.
Mob, there's no mistaking it this time.
We are being watched.
Wait, what's with that shirt?
Why are you taking your jacket off?
It's getting pretty hot from
all the running, so...
Just put it back on,
your jacket provides defences...
You're trying to do something
to the Divine Tree, huh?
You two can't do anything about it.
Arataka Reigen.
I heard you're planning
to cut down the Divine Tree.
It seems like I need to scold you...
Hey, they're running away!
Dammit!
I think most of the citizen has been
turned into Psycho Helmet followers.
How did it end up like this?
What should we do?
Psycho Helmet is an unknown psychic.
We don't even know what he's thinking,
moreover his goals.
I'm sure he'll show up on our way
if we head to the Divine Tree.
If he's a bad guy, take him out and
free everyone from the brainwash.
Hey, Mob.
What do you think about
the Psycho Helmet Religion?
Do you think they're bad guys?
No, I don't think they're bad people.
They just seem like a bunch of people
having fun together.
You think so, too?
-I also...
-But...
It changed once the founder showed up.
If he's a fake and tricked everyone
into worshipping him,
I don't like how he does things.
But Mob,
there's no real one to begin with.
How can you say that he's a fake?
Huh?
What, are you implying that
you're actually the true Psycho Helmet?
No...
Since the beginning, there was only
a pretence that a founder even exists.
I don't think that
Psycho Helmet is a bad guy.
Every community needs a leader.
Just think of it as the leader of a fan club.
Sounds normal enough.
He pretty much manages activity policy
and ensures smooth operation.
Must be hard work.
He's doing what you can't do, Mob.
But don't hold a grudge against him.
It's a festival.
Those who have fun win.
If they need the Divine Tree, then
it's not good to take it from them.
All right, let's go home for today, Mob.
Master Reigen.
This is just a guess,
but are you brainwashed?
Me?
Oh, I see...
So this is how it feels like, being told
you're brainwashed even if that's not true.
Try to prioritize the citizen's hearts
over the city itself.
Every single citizen has turned into
a follower of the Psycho Helmet Religion.
We should consider
their feelings too, right?
From now on, this city,
or this world,
they need to live symbiotically with the
Divine Tree and Psycho Helmet Religion, so...
Hey, Mob! I'm not coming with you!
Hey!
I hope I'm just mistaken...
But those people...
And those people...
Even those people...
Maybe I'm the only one
in this city that hasn't...
Are you going to meet him?
Yeah...
I want to see him directly,
and ask some questions.
Oh?
Everyone, give him a space.
Mob is coming through.
I can hear Lord Psycho Helmet's voice.
Shigeo Kageyama is the original
Lord Psycho Helmet!
Oh, this is amazing!
The original Lord Psycho Helmet
has returned!
There are two Lord Psycho Helmet!
We have a double founder!
Yay!
This is getting better and better!
-What a wonderful man.
-Psycho Helmet! Psycho Helmet!
-How admirable!
Psycho Helmet! Psycho Helmet!
Psycho Helmet!
Now now, calm down, Mob.
Are you really going to beat up
Lord Psycho Helmet?
Think again carefully,
this is for your own sake, okay?
Next on episode 5 of
Mob Psycho 100 III,
"Divine Tree 2 ~Peace~"
Illegal download?
You're going to get cursed.